Luis Alberto Garnica López



311 187 4302



Fresno #910 La Huerta, Guadalupe, Nuevo León

https://www.luisgarnica.ml

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/lagl95

WHO AM I

Computational Systems Engineer, master's in computer sciences student, 25 years.

I love to test myself with different challenges, which have taken me to a better development of my self-learning abilities. In general, I feel that I adapt myself very easily when It is about teamwork.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

October 2016 -May 2017 (Tepic, Nayarit)

Centro de Investigación y Desarrollo en Tecnologías de la Información (CIDETI), which belongs to Instituto Tecnológico de Tepic,

Android & MEAN Developer

Tasks:

I Developed an Android App named FindMe TecNM, to connect students of Tecnológico Nacional de México with employers. For the backend MongoDB, NodeJS and Nginx were used, in a Linux droplet from Digital Ocean. The client mobile app was developed using lava.

Augusto 2017 – January 2018 (Tepic, Nayarit)

January 2018 – January 2019

(Monterrey,

Nuevo León)

MX Global Solutions,

C# Developer

Tasks:

I worked in a desktop Project named FincaLab, a custom software to ensure coffee quality and processing. It was desktop software and used a SQL Server relational database, mostly through Stored Procedures. In this job I worked with Visual C# & SQL Server.

Dotech S.A. de C.V.,

Analyst Developer

Tasks:

I was in different web (Java EE & ASP.NET) and desktop (C#) projects. I worked with Oracle RMS ERP customizations for 7-Eleven. In databases I managed Oracle and MySQL. I performed several activities depending on the Project and the client requirements. Agile Development with SCRUM methodology.

EDUCATION

2019-2020

Master's in computer sciences

Tecnológico de Monterrey Monterrey, Nuevo León

2013-2018

Computational Systems Engineer

Instituto Tecnológico de Tepic. Tepic, Nayarit

repic, Nayarii

2010-2013

Computers Technician

Centro de Estudios Tecnológicos Industrial y de Servicios No 100. "Josefa Ortiz de Domínguez".

Tepic, Nayarit

ABILITIES

- Software Development (Java, C#, Python).
- Android Mobile apps development (Java).
- Cross-Platform mobile app development using frameworks (lonic).
- NoSQL Database Administration (MongoDB).
- Relational database administration (Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL).
- Control version software experience (Git, Team Foundation Server, Bit Bucket).
- Knowledge in HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- Basic Knowledge in Linux Operating System.
- General Knowledge in Machine Learnina.
- Neural Networks (Python/Keras).

PROGRAMING LANGUAGES

 Java
 • • • • • •

 Python
 • • • • •

 C#
 • • • • • •

 TypeScript
 • • • • • •

DBMS

JavaScript

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

 English: Intermediate/Advanced TOEFL ITP: 643 pts.